（泰国）
过来！看这边！
Come on! Look at here!
-这是什么？ -哗！恶心死了！
-What's that? -So gross!
正点啊！
Cool shot!
咦？到了吗？
Are we there already?
到了到了 下车！
Yes! Let's go.
走呀！
Move!
怎么了？
Funny…
为什么停车？
Why are we stopping here?
再见
Bye.
（报德善堂救援队）
POH TECK TUNG RESCUE UNIT
天啊…
Oh, shit!
-哦 该死！ -哦 该死！
-Oh, shit! -Oh, shit!
我靠！你找死啊？这种东西你也拍！
Oh, shit! You moron! How dare you tape that?
-把它关掉！ -是 是 是！
-Cut that out! -Okay!
叫你关掉啊！
You heard me!
我也要
Give me some!
这种环境最适合讲鬼故事
This is the best time for telling horror stories.
有没有听过一个 关于七月十四的鬼故事？
Ever hear about the story of All Souls' Day?
七月十四有那么多 谁知你说是哪个？
Depends on which year's All Souls' Day, right?
就是嘛！
Exactly!
有没有听说过这个
This is the one concerning
我朋友的舅舅是开报摊的
my friend's uncle who owned a newsstand.
今年七月十四
On the last All Souls' Day,
在自己报摊那里
right in his shop,
见到了！
he had an encounter!
那天四点多
It was just after 4:00 a.m.
天还没亮
It was still dark.
他就像平常一样正在整理报纸
He was stacking the papers like usual.
陈先生 你好！
Hi there, Mr. Chan!
帮个忙啊！
Do me a favor!
帮我叫救护车
Call an ambulance!
这个婆婆…
Granny here,
她…她说很不舒服…
she said she's not feeling well.
怎么样？是不是吓到爆啊？
How about that? Scary?
小儿科
Hell no!
还是听听我的吧！
Listen to mine!
这个故事发生在我朋友的哥哥的干妹妹身上
This story happened to the god-sister of my friend's brother.
他们一家人住在佐敦消防局宿舍里
They lived at the apartments for firemen.
在两年前的一个晚上
It was one evening two years ago.
那天晚上很冷
It was cold…
八度左右
about eight degrees Celsius.
我朋友的哥哥的干妹妹睡到两点钟
This god-sister slept until 2:00 a.m.,
突然听到操场有步操的声音
then she heard people drilling outside.
她就觉得很奇怪啦
She thought, "How strange!
一个大冷天
It's far too cold
消防队员没有理由这么早就出操啊？
and too early for the firemen to be drilling."
于是 她就走出去看一看
So, she got up to take a look.
她不看还好
Too bad she did
一看就…
because…
她竟然被其中一个日本兵发现
One of the Japanese soldiers spotted her.
那日本鬼子对着她大喝一声
He yelled at her,
把武士刀拔了出来
pulled out his samurai sword
向她冲过去！
and charged right at her!
那女孩子有没有死掉？
Was the girl killed?
那女的啊？
No.
她疯了 进了精神病院
But she went nuts afterwards.
喂喂喂！
Listen!
我听过一个真人真事呢 超恐怖啊！
There is this true story. It's super gross!
我朋友在泰国听着鬼故事吃鱿鱼丝
A friend of mine was listening to a ghost story,
噎死了！
and she died choking!
噎死你啊 吃那么多！
Cut down the snacks, or you'll die!
来！干杯！干杯！
-Come on! -Cheers!
干杯！
-Cheers! -Yeah!
你们的鬼故事不是朋友就是表弟的
Your horror stories don't involve you personally.
说真的 有亲眼见过吗？
Frankly, did any of you have an encounter before?
没事的时候看看书嘛！
You guys should read more often!
（《见鬼十法》）
10 WAYS TO SEE… GHOSTS
什么东东啊？
What's that?
怎么了？
What?
这本书记载了
This is about the 10 ways
泰国流传的10种见鬼的方法
to encounter ghosts. It's from ancient Thai legends.
这可不是随随便便可以买得到的
You can't find this book just anywhere.
有天晚上我搭错车
One evening, I took the wrong bus,
又下错站
then got off at the wrong stop.
刚巧一家书店还没关门
A book store was still open,
就进去问路了！
so, I went in for directions.
有没有人啊？哈啰？
Anyone in? Hello?
（《见鬼十法》）
THE TEN ENCOUNTERS
（你不相信我 会后悔的！）
THIRD WAY TO SEE A GHOST - OUIJA
想看的话 就买回家里去看
Pay first, and read later…
这本书多少钱啊？
How much is it?
我看你跟这本书很有缘分
It's karma that brought you to this book.
就便宜点卖给你
I'll give you a discount, then.
500铢好了！
How about 500 baht?
你这不是抢钱吗！
You must be kidding!
嫌便宜啊？
Too cheap?
那么照原价好了
Then pay me the full price!
500就500吧！
Here's your 500.
哎！听着 这本书
Listen up, kiddo.
千万别翻到最后一页！
Don't ever turn to the last page of the book.
看了会有不幸的事情发生啊！
Or else, misfortune will come to you!
不相信 你一定会后悔的！
You'll regret it if you don't believe me!
可是不幸的事情始终发生了！
Still, I cannot avoid misfortune!
千万别翻到最后一页
Don't you ever turn to the last page!
定价：100铢
"Price: 100 baht."
特价：50铢？我靠！
"Discount Price: 50 baht?" Bastard!
靠…好差劲耶！
Moron!
一个老头子就能把你唬了！
Even an old man can fool you!
可是这书里面的方法
Man, this book was the real thing.
确实是有根据的
The rituals were authentic.
其中两个方法 还有真人真事的个案呢！
And I can tell you about two cases to back it up!
第一是换死人眼角膜
The first one was "the condemned cornea transplant".
第二个呢
The second one
女人才行：怀孕的时候去自杀！
was for women only. To attempt suicide while pregnant!
这两个我好像也听过
I think I've heard about these two cases before.
我也好像听过…
Me too.
对吧？
You see?
哎？这干什么？瑜珈术啊？
What's this? Yoga?
是“倒头栽”！ 泰国人相信这样可以见到鬼！
It's "Between-the-Knees Peek", a Thai custom still practiced today!
长贵啊
Chongkwai.
还有些什么其它的方法啊？
What are the other ways?
我看看
Let me see.
这个是十二点整梳头
Comb your hair at midnight,
就会在镜子里看到你想看的鬼了！
and the ghost you desire will appear in the mirror.
还有啊
Next.
干嘛？他长针眼啊？
Jesus. Something is wrong with his eyes?
书上说啊
The book says,
用葬过死人的泥巴涂眼睛
rub the graveyard soil over your eyes,
就会看到鬼世界了！
and you'll be exposed to the world of the spirits!
有没有再简单又安全一点的方法啊？
Aren't there any simpler and safer ways?
有 简单点嘛
Sure! Here's a simpler way.
在屋里打伞！
Open an umbrella indoors.
保证见鬼！
You'll score for sure!
你是说
So,
照着这些方法玩 就一定能见到鬼了？
if we follow the instructions, we'll get to see ghosts for sure?
也不一定
It depends.
不同的人玩有不同的成功率
Different players have different success rates.
说到这里 没道理不试试看吧？
Why not try it out, then?
对啊 对啊！
Damn right!
不玩我们今夜怎么过？对不对？
We need a game to get through the night!
唔…就是嘛！
Why not?
不是说有成功率吗？
Given that there are different success rates,
也就是…不一定见得到啰！啊？
we might not get to see them at all, right?
对啊
Right.
那么你们听清楚
Then listen carefully.
游戏一旦开始了
Once the game has started,
无论中途发生了什么事也绝不可以停
we can't quit playing, no matter what happens.
否则的话就会大祸临头
Or else, misfortune will come to us.
不怕死的话
You've heard me.
现在就开始吧！
Now, let's begin!
先试个最容易的！
Let's try the most convenient way!
泰国人的杯仙
The Thai "Spirits in a Glass"
跟中国人的碟仙、老外的巫师板
is like the Chinese Plate Genie and the Westerner's Ouija Board.
杯仙
THE SPIRITS IN A GLASS
根本就是一模一样
They are all alike.
都是请鬼来在纸上把文字逐一指出来
That is, they all invite a ghost to spell out his messages.
哎呀…动了…动了
Shit, it's moving.
讨厌死了！你吓人啊你！
You moron! That's not funny!
-来了…好害怕啊！ -不要再乱动啊！
-God. It's here! -Stop shuffling!
"Reak…
chan…
ma…
tum…
mai."
叫我有事吗？
Why are you calling me?
喂！
Hey!
我日
Fuck you!
妈啊！你干嘛不睡啊？
Mom! Why are you still up?
这么晚 吓死我朋友啦！
You're scaring my friends!
啍！你怎么不说
Serves you right!
是我被你们吵死了呢！
You guys are killing my ears!
现在几点了 还不去睡觉！
It's late already! Go to bed now!
我知道了 你先睡吧
Okay, after you.
不好意思
Sorry, guys.
我妈昨天晚上才帮人家做了一夜的法
My mom did some heavy channeling last night.
她要休息 我们小声一点！
She needs to rest. We'd better be quiet.
原来你妈是帮人家作法术的啊！
So, your mom is a spiritual medium?
怪不得样子邪邪的
No wonder she looks kind of weird.
THE LATE DINNER ALERT
泰国人相信
Thai people believe that
十字路口是阴气最盛
where roads cross, there is a lot of negative power.
孤魂野鬼最多的地方
It's a favorite hangout for stray spirits.
想看到他们
To catch a glimpse of them,
就要带着三菜一汤、饭碗和筷子
go to an intersection after midnight
在午夜之后找个十字路口等着
with a meal for three, and bowls and chopsticks.
我们的目标
Our target,
是那些饿鬼
the hungry ghosts.
等一下要不停的敲你们的碗
Hey! Later you tap the bowl with the chopsticks
那些饿鬼就会自动来吃饭了！
and hungry ghosts will come out for the food.
真的会有效吗？
Is this really going to work?
当然了！书是这样说的！试试看！
Of course! Believe me, it's a sure thing!
待会见到鬼 千万不要叫啊！
When you see them, don't scream, okay?
你管你自己啦！ 待会你可不要吓跑啊！
Look who's talking! Just don't run away in front of me!
敲碗的时候 千万不能停
Once you start tapping the bowl, do not stop!
一停下来 那些鬼就会看到你！
If you stop, the ghosts will see you.
鬼一上身就糟糕了 知道吗？
You don't want to risk being possessed, okay?
开始吧！
Let's roll!
干嘛？
What is it?
什么事？干什么嘛？
What's the matter?
冷静点 继续敲 别停
Stay cool, keep on tapping.
你看到什么？
What did you see?
干什么？怎么了？怎么了？
What is it? What's going on?
你看到什么？
What did you see?
没有啊！
I didn't see a thing!
-什么啊？ -有没有看到？
-What is it? -Did you see that?
冷静点 冷静点…
Stay cool!
继续敲不要停！
Keep tapping!
什么啦？
What?
-干嘛！ -你看到什么了嘛！
-What's wrong? -What did you see?
-你看到什么了嘛！ -啊？怎么啦？
-What did you see? -What now?
我见到了！
I see them!
继续敲啊！不要停啊！
Keep tapping!
冷静冷静！继续敲！
Stay cool! Tap!
什么事啊？
What's wrong?
继续敲！
Tap!
我什么都没见到啊！
I see nothing!
喂！我怎么什么都没见到！
Hey! I didn't get to see anything!
你们见到什么啦？高辉？
What is it that you see, Gofei?
-那边… -那边？我看不到什么啊！
-Over there! -But there's nothing there!
为什么你们通通都看到 就我看不到？
It's not fair! Everybody got to see them except me!
我不是说过每个人 对鬼的感应不一样嘛
Told you we all have different reception of ghosts.
你可能是一辈子 都见不到鬼的那种人！
Maybe you're just the type who can't see them!
长贵 还有没有其他方法啊？
Chongkwai, are there any other ways?
你们不要翘头啊！
Don't you guys chicken out now!
我今天一定要见到鬼！
I've got to see ghosts tonight!
PLAYING HIDE N' SEEK
半夜抱黑猫玩捉迷藏 鬼就会一起玩
Play Hide n' Seek at midnight carrying a black cat.
鬼呢 会挡住我们其中一个
Ghosts will come join us
让我们看不到那个人
and block one of us from our view.
那个时候放出黑猫
We then let go of the black cat.
黑猫就可以让鬼现形
The cat can make the ghost appear before us.
那么我们不但可以找到那个人
Not only will we find that missing person,
还可以…见鬼！
we can also see the ghost.
不玩了！快点出来吧！
I quit! Come back out!
不玩了！
I quit!
爸爸！这是什么水啊？爸爸…
Papa! What's this stinky water?
找不到啊！
Where is he?
怎么办？
What now?
有鬼挡着高辉 所以找不到
I think a ghost is blocking Gofei.
不要怕 不要怕 我放猫啊…
It's okay. I'm letting the cat go now.
小黑带路啊！带路啊！
Ebony, lead the way!
高辉！高辉！
Gofei! Gofei!
-高辉！高辉！ -前面呀！
-Gofei! -Over there!
小黑…好像…好像死掉了！
Ebony seems dead!
连猫都死了？
Even the cat is dead?
那现在怎么办啊？高辉怎么办呀？
What do we do now? What happened to Gofei?
现在怎么办啊？高辉到哪儿去了？
What do we do? Where the hell is he?
-高辉！ -高辉！
-Gofei! -Gofei!
高辉！不要玩了！出来啦！
Gofei, we quit the game! Come back out!
高辉不玩了！
Gofei, call it off!
-高辉！ -高辉！
-Gofei! -Gofei!
高辉！
Gofei!
-Gofei! -Gofei!
高辉！
Gofei!
喂？高辉！高辉！喂？
Hello? Gofei! Gofei!? Hello?
怎么啦 艾普尔？ 不要吓我 电话没响过啊！
April, you okay? The phone didn't even ring!
电话刚刚明明有响啊！
No, it did ring!
你别这样啦 警察说会继续找的啊
Don't worry too much! The police will stay on it.
一定会把高辉找回来的！
We will find Gofei for sure!
全都是你害的
It's all your fault.
你们先走吧 回香港等消息吧！
You'd better go back to Hong Kong first.
有些事情 警察也帮不上忙
The police might not be able to help this time.
-伯母可是… -不要再说了
-But, Auntie-- -Just listen to me.
可以走就最好赶快走
Leave while you still can.
只怕有人不甘愿
Someone could be setting you up.
要跟你们玩下去 那就糟了！
I don't think you can defend yourselves!
（见鬼十法 涂尸泥）
THE SPECIAL EYE MASK
艾普尔 ！
April!
不要啊！
Don't!
艾普尔 ！
April! April,
艾普尔！你怎么样啊？
are you okay?
艾普尔 闭上眼睛！千万别张开…
April! Close your eyes, don't open them,
还没有好
not now!
眼睛闭上 听我说
Close them tight. Listen to me!
现在张开眼会出事啊！
You'll be in trouble if you open them now!
不要怕！是我们啦！没有事的！
We're here for you! You'll be okay!
你再等一下
Hold on for just one more second.
好！行了！眼睛可以挣开了
Okay, now, you can open your eyes.
-喂 艾普尔 ！ -怎么了 艾普尔？
-Hey, April! -April, you all right?
好痛啊！
It hurts!
好可怕！我眼睛掉了！我眼睛掉了！
It was so scary! My eyes, they fell out!
开玩笑嘛
No way.
你眼睛还在啊
Your eyes are still there.
没事了！别害怕 什么事都没了！
Don't worry, everything's okay now!
还好 你们还来得及去救她回来！
You guys were lucky to save her in time!
知不知道 刚才很危险啊！ 她差一点就进冥界去了
She almost slipped into the spirit world!
进去之后就出不来了！
If she did, she'd be trapped forever!
长贵！你不是小孩子 做人要负责任！
Chongkwai! You should know better not to play with fire!
你们什么东西不好玩？
You're not a child anymore!
伯母说什么？
What did Auntie say?
是不是知道高辉在哪里啊？
Does she know where Gofei is?
我妈在怪我
My mom blamed me
教你用尸泥涂眼睛
for teaching you the use of graveyard soil.
害你差一点掉入冥界
I nearly caused you to be trapped in the spirit world.
对不起啊
I'm so sorry.
我没想过会搞成这样！
I never thought things would turn out like this!
你们不懂的事情太多了
There're too many things that you don't know.
这个世界有不同的空间
There are other dimensions in this world!
你们懂不懂？
Do you understand?
除了我们人的阳界 鬼的冥界
Apart from our human world,
还有很多很多我们不知道的空间
there are numerous unknown dimensions.
艾普尔啊 还好你刚才没有掉进冥界去
April was lucky not to slip into the other world.
在我小时候 就亲眼见过一个女孩子
When I was a kid, I saw this young woman.
她不小心走进了冥界！
She entered that world by mistake.
放我出去！放我出去！
Let me out!
以后要记住
Now you know!
玩这种东西是非常危险的
Always stay away from black magic.
出了事情的话
When things get out of hand,
你们谁也应付不了！知道吗？
you won't be able to survive the consequences.
那现在高辉到哪儿去了？
But where is Gofei now?
不知道
Who knows?
我不是说过不要留在这里吗？ 回香港吧！
Just don't stay here! Go back to Hong Kong now!
不行！我不回去！ 我要留下来找高辉！
No! I won't leave without Gofei!
表姐
Cousin.
就这样走了 是不是太没道义呢？
Wouldn't it be kind of low if we just leave?
这样子走掉 真的是没道义
If we leave, yes, it is low.
绝对不可以做出这种事情！
Then we shouldn't do it!
可是…
But then…
车已经来了
the cab is here already.
道义这东西…上了车再说吧！
Low or not low, we can discuss that on the way!
臭孩子！一点道义都没有
Scumbags! How could they ditch April like this?
丢下艾普尔就跑掉了！
You call them your friends?
回到香港我就没有跟得仔联络了
I didn't talk to Ted after we were back to Hong Kong.
他也没有找我
He didn't call me, either.
可能大家都想把泰国的事忘了吧
Maybe he just wants to forget about what happened.
我也想
Me too.
可是我知道是不可能的
But I know it's not possible.
回来那几个礼拜 长贵还有打电话来
For the first two weeks, Chongkwai did call.
可是我不太敢问他艾普尔的事
I didn't dare ask him about April, though.
不知道她现在怎么样了
I wonder how she is now…
我就装得像正常一样继续上课、下课
I pretend everything's normal. I go to school.
逛街、吃饭啰
I play, I eat, I go out.
对哦 如果真的很正常
Damn right, everything is normal.
又何必要装呢？
So, why am I pretending?
先生！
Mister!
有没有人啊？
Anyone in?
（《见鬼十法》）
THE TEN ENCOUNTERS
（杯仙）
THE SPIRITS IN A GLASS
那男人跟高辉失踪的事一定有关！
This man has got to have something to do with Gofei!
他还在书里画了我们五个人 玩杯仙呢！
He even drew the five of us playing the damn game!
笨蛋！
Bonehead!
他啊 明明就是给你下了降头！
It's obvious that he's cast a spell on all of you!
这个劫 你们几个是绝对没办法解的！
You guys just can't overcome this on your own!
（午夜梳头）
（室内打伞）
干什么？吓死人啊？
What's wrong with you?
球你也怕！
It's only a ball!
（倒头栽）
THE BETWEEN-THE-KNEES PEEK
接吧 说不定有急事！
It's disturbing! Answer it! Maybe it's urgent!
好！
Okay!
得仔啊！这次是真的 真的见鬼啦！
Teddy? This time, I really saw it!
又见鬼啊？这次在哪里看到的啊？
You saw ghosts again? Where was it this time?
在家里门口啊！
Right outside my front door!
不要想那么多 喝喝酒 很快就忘了！
Have a drink, and you won't remember it.
你不要再装了 骗不了自己的！
Don't play dumb anymore, it's no use!
真的有只鬼在我们家门口打球啊！
There is a ghost playing ball outside!
你马上给我回来啊！
Just come over now!
你是不是眼花啊？
Are you sure?
你才眼花呢
Hundred percent!
我刚才按长贵说的倒着头 才看得到他啊！
I did the Between-the-Knees Peek bending over and I saw him!
难道还会有错吗？
I am so very sure!
那…我…那…
Then, I…
还那什么 马上给我回来啊！
Cut the crap and come over now!
我知道了！
Okay, I will.
我先走了
Well, I must go.
你去哪啊？
Where are you going?
Hello?
阿美？长贵啊！艾普尔失踪了？
May? It's Chongkwai! April has vanished!
呀？
What?
你们没事吧？ 我们已经有两个人出事了
Already two people among us have disappeared.
我妈叫你跟得仔千万要小心啊！
My mom wants you guys to be careful!
（4号梯 3号梯）
这么晚电梯还这么挤？
Why is it still so crowded so late at night?
UNIT 12C
哥哥 你有没有看到我的成绩单？
Mister, have you seen my report card?
嗯！你这小鬼！
You little damn thing!
对不起啊
Sorry.
我以为你是鬼啊！
I thought you were a ghost!
不要哭 对不起哦！
Don't cry. I'm sorry!
哪来这么多的鬼啊？
So, what if there are ghosts?
呀？
找死？
Messing with us?
干什么？
What are you doing?
这是什么地方？
Where am I?
进来再说！
It's dangerous here.
得仔啊！
Teddy!
你来了就好了！
Thank God you're here!
喂！你不要哭了 坐下来再说
Don't cry. Come sit down first.
我们这次真的死定了
We are dead meat.
我们见鬼了
I see ghosts all the time!
我看泰国的事情还没完
Our problem has not ended just there in Thailand.
你记不记得长贵说过
Remember what Chongkwai said?
只要一开始玩这个游戏
Once we've started the game,
不管中途发生什么事情 都不可以停啊！
we just can't quit playing until it's all over!
闹得这么严重
Looks like we must return to Thailand before
要回泰国找长贵才能搞得定
we can settle everything.
哎？那个女的呢？
Where's that girl?
你在找什么？
What are you looking for?
我朋友啊 跟我一起进来那个女孩子啊
My friend, the girl who came in with me! The one from Thailand!
你记不记得 在泰国那个啊 跟我们一起坐车那个啊
We shared the same bus ride together, remember?
喂！没事了！出来吧
It's okay, now! Come out!
可是…可是从头到尾
I think I only saw you
我只看到你一个人进来啊！
coming in alone!
你干嘛看这些带子？
Why are you watching these tapes?
你不要跟我说…
Don't tell me…
她已经进来了
she's here.
可是我现在看不到她啊
But I can't see her now.
你要不要试试倒着头看一下？
Wanna try and look between your legs?
怎么看啊？
But how?
倒…
Bend over.
头…
看！
Hey!
我们这样做很危险啊！
We shouldn't be doing this! It's too risky!
难道要我们这样等死吗？
Our lives are at stake, anyway!
我就拼死试最后这个办法 看会怎样！
This method could be our last resort!
表姐啊
Cousin,
还是看一看再说嘛
let's think it over!
你不去是吗？我不会勉强你的！
You're not in this with me, right? Suit yourself!
哎呀！
Wait!
我不是这个意思喇
That's not what I mean.
我陪你去
I'm in.
（终极见鬼方法）
THE LAST FRONTIER
DEATH
到冥界去
To advance your death,
要穿上一套死人穿过的寿衣装死
you have to play dead wearing a used funeral suit,
你们只有一柱香的时间
and then you can infiltrate the spirit world.
到时候 我会用招魂铃声叫你们走的
Your time there is limited and you must leave on time.
你们一听到铃声
Once you hear me ringing a bell,
马上跟着白光走！千万不要等啊！
enter the stream of white light!
不然的话 香烧完了
It's your only way out. Don't delay,
你们就回不来了！
or you'll never get back!
完了…
Damn…
还是睡不着
I still can't fall asleep.
怎么办呢…
What a drag.
那么… 我帮你！
Then let me help you!
-我们去了哪里啊？ -我哪知道
-Where are we? -Don't know.
完了…
Damn…
-我有点怕耶 -我…
-I'm kind of scared. -I…
也怕耶！
I'm scared, too!
喂！
Wait!
鬼啊！
A ghost!
他还对我们笑呢！
But he is smiling!
对啊！长贵说过
That's right! Chongkwai said,
我们不惹那些鬼 他们就不会来惹我们
if we don't meddle with them, they won't bother us!
还蛮可爱的嘛！
This one is kind of cute!
你看他们对我们也蛮友善的哦！
Hey, they seem quite friendly, too!
喂
There!
上面！
Up there!
不对劲耶！好像越来越多鬼啊！
Something's not right! It's getting crowded here!
这边的不笑了也不太友善耶
And they aren't smiling, not so friendly anymore, either.
哎！快想个办法啦！
Quick, think of something!
我想不到啊！
I can't!
记不记得长贵说过
Didn't Chongkwai say
他们会怕我们的阳气啊！
that ghosts are afraid of the smell of our breath?
是吗？
He said that?
唔！
Well…
哎！真的可以啊！
It works!
喂！你好臭啊！
Man, you stink!
起来！走啦！
Get up! Let's go!
没有再追来了
They've stopped hunting us.
得仔你怎么样？
How are you doing, Ted?
我要休息一下
I need to rest!
我也是
So do I.
小心啊 表姐！
Be careful, cousin!
还是被你们找到了 没意思 我不玩了！
You found me, how boring! I quit!
高辉！
Gofei!
你没事太好了！我们终于找到你了！
Thank God you're all right! We've finally found you!
喂！才一下子不见 干嘛哭成这样子？
Calm down, girl! You haven't seen me for only an hour!
你们到哪里去了？
Where were you guys?
-不！你已经失踪一个月啦！ -一个月？
-Listen! You were gone for a month! -A month?
我们出事了！
We messed up!
你被小鬼挡住 我们整一个月都找不到你
A ghost has blocked you from our view all this while.
所以我和表姐装死人 来冥界找你
We played dead to come here for you in the spirit world.
呀？冥界…
这里…是冥界？
This is… the spirit world?
对啊！
Yes!
完了！我真的没有气了
It's all over! I'm pooped.
我也没了
Same here.
高辉 你是新来的
Gofei, you're new here.
你放点阳气吓他们啊！
Greet them with your breath!
阳气？
My breath?
是啊！
Yes!
怎么放啊？
What do you mean?
他们会怕的
They're afraid of it.
要怎么放啊？
But how?
我真的不行了！我真的没有气了！
I really can't do this anymore! I'm breathless!
你还不出绝招？
Show them your specialty!
你还有没有屁放啊？
You can still fart, can't you?
高辉！
Gofei!
-你在哪里啊？ -艾普尔？
-Where are you? -April?
-我来陪你啊！ -艾普尔？
-I've come to stay with you! -April?
-高辉！ -是艾普尔啊！
-Gofei! -It's April!
艾普尔 这里啊！
April! I'm here!!!
高辉？是不是你啊？
Gofei? Is that you?
真的是艾普尔啊！
Yes! It's April!
对啊 对啊！是艾普尔啊！
-高辉！ -艾普尔！
-Gofei! -April!
喂！快点跟我走！快点啊！
Come with me now! Hurry!
听到没有啊？
You hear that?
有啊！
I do!
听到没有 我们这下有救了！
Do you hear that? We are safe now!
-是长贵啊！ -是啊！
-It's Chongkwai! -It is!
什么长贵啊？
What about him?
长贵说听到了铃声然后跟着白光走
He said, run to the white light once we hear the bell,
就可以走出去了！
and we'd be out!
是吗？
Really?
是啊！
Yes!
真的有白光耶！我们走吧！走啊…
There it is! Let's go to the light now!
什么铃声什么白光啊？
What white light? What bell?
为什么我什么都听不到 看不到呢？
How come I don't hear or see any of these?
你怎么会到这里来的？
How did you get here?
高辉
Gofei,
我以为你已经死了
I thought you were dead.
所以我才会…
That's why I…
妈！香快烧完了 怎么办啊？
Mom! We're running out of time! Do something!
表姐 现在怎么办啊？ 我们走不走啊？
Cousin, what do we do now? Are we leaving or not?
喂！
Hey!
你们走吧！我留下来！
You guys go ahead! I'm staying!
走啦！
Just go!
快点啊！
Hurry!
阿美
May!
伯母！
Auntie!
长贵！
Chongkwai!
伯母！
Auntie!
得仔！
Teddy!
我早就说过了
I told you.
你们斗不过他的！
This is a curse you can't overcome!
（《见鬼十法》）
（杯仙）
对这本书有兴趣？
Interested in this book?
那么我便宜点卖给你吧
What if I give you a discount?
好不好？
You like that?